<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Raphaële Slimane&#39;s corner</title>
<link>https://www.slimaneraphaele.com/blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://www.slimaneraphaele.com/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>posts de blog.</description>
<image>
<url>https://www.slimaneraphaele.com/images/childrenillustration/illustrationenfant2.png</url>
<title>Raphaële Slimane&#39;s corner</title>
<link>https://www.slimaneraphaele.com/blog.html</link>
<height>127</height>
<width>144</width>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.7.34</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Bienvenue / Welcome</title>
  <dc:creator>Raphaële Slimane</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.slimaneraphaele.com/blog/1_2025_03_04_bienvenue/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="bienvenue-sur-mon-site" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bienvenue-sur-mon-site">Bienvenue sur mon site !</h2>
<p>Salut et bienvenue ! Je suis Raphaële Slimane, illustratrice. Ici, je partage mon travail : illustrations jeunesse, <em>urban sketching</em>, mélanges entre techniques traditionnelles et digitales (<em>Procreate</em>), fanart et créations de personnages. Je vais aussi partager mes dessins du quotidien et mes expérimentations techniques.</p>
<p>J’alterne entre peinture, encre, crayons et Ipad, selon l’inspiration et le projet. Le dessin a toujours été une passion, mais j’ai commencé l’illustration digitale en 2023. Depuis, j’explore de nouvelles manières de créer avec Procreate, tout en continuant à travailler avec des outils traditionnels. J’aime tester, apprendre et progresser, et je partagerai ici mes découvertes et mon évolution. Je vis à Paris, entourée de bouquins, toujours un carnet à la main. À côté de ça, j’ai un job la journée, mais le dessin reste mon terrain de jeu principal.</p>
<p>J’écris mes contenus en français et en anglais : en français, parce que c’est ma langue maternelle, et en anglais, pour échanger avec une communauté artistique qui ne se limite pas à la France. Envie de discuter, de collaborer sur un projet ou juste d’échanger ? Vous pouvez me contacter via Instagram (<span class="citation" data-cites="slimaneraphaele">@slimaneraphaele</span>).</p>
</section>
<section id="welcome-to-my-site" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="welcome-to-my-site">Welcome to my site!</h2>
<p>Hi, and welcome! I’m Raphaële Slimane, an illustrator navigating between different styles and media. Here, you’ll find a mix of children’s illustrations, urban sketching, explorations of traditional and digital techniques (<em>Procreate</em>), fanart, and character design. I’ll also be sharing my daily sketches and technical experiments.</p>
<p>I work with paint, ink, pencils, and iPad, depending on the project and the mood. Drawing has always been a passion, but I started digital illustration in 2023. Since then, I’ve been diving into Procreate, while still working with traditional media. I love testing new things, learning, and improving, and I’ll be sharing my progress and discoveries along the way. I live in Paris, surrounded by books and rarely without a sketchbook. By day, I have a more conventional job, but illustration is where my focus really is.</p>
<p>I write my content in both French and English—French because it’s my native language, and English to connect with the wider artistic community beyond France. Interested in collaborating, discussing a project, or just saying hi? You can reach me on Instagram (<span class="citation" data-cites="slimaneraphaele">@slimaneraphaele</span>).</p>


</section>

<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <category>blogging</category>
  <guid>https://www.slimaneraphaele.com/blog/1_2025_03_04_bienvenue/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.slimaneraphaele.com/blog/1_2025_03_04_bienvenue/illustrationenfant2.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="127" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
